奥尼尔，我们得继续跑，快，起来
O'Neil, we've gotta keep going. Come on, get up.
没用的，到处都是他们的人
It's no use. They're everywhere.
舰长有令
Captain gave us an order.
我们得找到些线索
We've gotta find some clue.
没用的，苏鲁，看，那就有一个
It's no use, Mr. Sulu. Look, there's one of them.
那又有一个
There's another one.
侦查组呼叫进取号
Scouting party to Enterprise.
接进来
Come in.
怎么了，苏鲁？
What is it, Mr. Sulu?
舰长，快传送我们回去，情况紧急
Captain, beam us up quick. Emergency.
传送室，锁定苏鲁和奥尼尔
Transporter Room, lock onto Sulu and O'Neil.
把他们立即传送回来
Beam up immediately.
我们得快逃，不能傻站在这
We've gotta make a run for it. We can't just stand here.
奥尼尔，站直了，他们马上就传送我们回去
Mr. O'Neil, stand tight. They'll beam us up any minute.
快跑，我们必须离开这里
Run. We've gotta get out of here.
- 你知道他们的能力 - 奥尼尔
- You know what they're capable of. - O'Neil!
苏鲁，怎么回事，奥尼尔上尉呢？
Sulu, what is it? Where's Lieutenant O'Neil?
什么？
What?
- 谁？ - 奥尼尔上尉，他在哪儿？
- Who? - Lieutenant O'Neil. Where is he?
你
You.
你不属于躯壳
You're not of the Body.
麦考伊医生
Dr. McCoy.
麦考伊医生，快到传送室来
Dr. McCoy. Transporter Room, quickly.
你，你干的
You. You did it.
他们知道我们是“执政官”
They knew we were Archons.
这是他们穿的衣服
These are the clothes they wear.
不是这些
Not these.
苏鲁，别激动
Sulu, take it easy.
兰德鲁
Landru.
坐下
Sit down.
出什么事了？
What happened?
太美好了
They're wonderful.
他们是宇宙中最和蔼
They're the sweetest,
最友善的公民
friendliest people in the universe.
朋友们，那是天堂
It's paradise, my friend.
- 天堂 - 奥尼尔上尉在哪里？
- Paradise. - Lieutenant O'Neil. Where is he?
天堂
Paradise.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：胖收儿 小胖
校对：Micezhang
第一季第二十一集
执政官归来
舰长日志，星历3156.2
Captain's log, stardate 3156.2.
在环绕贝塔3号行星
While orbiting planet Beta III,
寻找一百年前消失的
trying to find some trace of the starship Archon
执政官号星舰的踪迹时
that disappeared here 100 years ago,
一支由两名进取号船员组成的侦查组
a search party consisting of two Enterprise officers
被送往下面的星球
was sent to the planet below.
苏鲁回来了
Mr. Sulu has returned,
但精神状态极度不安
but in a highly agitated mental state.
他的状况迫使我进行一次额外的搜索
His condition requires I beam down with an additional search detail.
传送完成，寇克完毕
Materialisation completed. Kirk out.
奇怪
Odd.
那人脸上的表情
The expression on that man's face.
神情恍惚
The mindlessness.
茫然无措
Vacant contentment.
跟苏鲁一样
Like Sulu.
如果这星球上的每个人都跟他一样的话…
If everybody on this planet is like him...
走
Let's go.
祝你们快乐，朋友们
Joy to you, friends.
祝你快乐
Joy to you.
你们是外地人
You be strangers.
- 来参加盛典的吗？ - 对
- Come for the Festival, eh, yeah? - Yes.
找到住处了？
Got a place to sleep it off yet?
去雷格家看看
Go round to Reger's house.
他那儿有房间
He's got rooms.
但你们得快点，血色时刻马上就到了
But you'll have to hurry. It's almost the Red Hour.
盛典，六点开始吗？
This Festival, it starts at 6:00?
图拉
Tula.
这些人是来参加盛典的
These folks come for the Festival.
你父亲能收留他们，对吧？
Your daddy can put them up, can't he?
你们从山谷来？
You're from the valley?
我们刚到
We've just arrived.
无论如何，我爸爸都会很乐意收留你们的
My father will be glad to put you up, though.
就在那边
It's right over there.
图拉！别
Tula! Come!
快撤
Let's get out of here.
很抱歉这样破门而入，我们没想到会受到这样的迎接
I'm sorry to break in on you like this. We didn't expect that kind of welcome.
迎接？你们是外地人？
Welcome? You are strangers?
对，我们从山谷来的
Yes, that's right. We're from the valley.
- 你们来参加盛典？ - 是的
- You came for the Festival? - Yes.
那你们怎么躲这儿了？
And how come you here?
- 你是雷格吗？ - 我是
- Are you Reger? - Yes.
- 你有个叫图拉的女儿？ - 对
- You have a daughter named Tula? - Yes.
你最好帮帮她，她在外面
Well, you'd better do something. She's outside.
我知道，是盛典
I know. It's Festival.
这是兰德鲁的意志
It's the will of Landru.
雷格，他们都是年轻人
Reger, these are young men.
没到足以逃避盛典的年纪
They're not old enough to be excused.
- 他们是客人 - 山谷里没有立法者吗？
- They are visitors. - Have they no Lawgivers in the valley?
他们为什么不参加盛典？
Why be they not at the Festival?
我们听说你或许可以给我们提供住处
We heard that you might have rooms for us.
你看，韩寇
There, you see, Hacom?
他们是来找地方歇脚的
They've come looking for a place to rest afterwards.
血色时刻已经爆发
The Red Hour has already struck.
韩寇，他们是外地人
Hacom, these be strangers.
山谷里跟我们这儿不一样
The valley has different ways.
你在否定兰德鲁无所不在吗？
Do you say that Landru is not everywhere?
不，当然不是，只是存在形式不同
No, of course not. It's simply that they may have different ways.
他们是来寻求庇护的
They've come looking for shelter.
我能赶他们走吗？
Can I turn them away?
请跟我来
Come, please.
但那个姑娘，外面那个
But the girl, out there.
她在参加盛典，你们本也该参加的
She is in Festival, as you should be.
跟我来，快
Come, please. Hurry.
立法者有权知晓
The Lawgivers should know.
当然，他们已经知道了
Surely, Hacom, they already know.
他们不是永远正确的吗？
Are they not infallible?
你嘲笑他们，你嘲笑立法者
You mock them. You mock the Lawgivers.
这些陌生人不属于躯壳
And the strangers are not of the Body.
你看着吧
You will see.
但是，韩寇
But, Hacom.
盛典结束你们可以回到这儿来
You can return here at close of Festival.
这儿很安静，你们应该需要休息
It's quiet. You will have need of rest.
先生，我们无意参加盛典
We have no plans to attend the Festival, sir.
血色时刻爆发了，你们听得到
The hour has struck. You can hear.
关于盛典，愿闻其详
I'd like to hear more about this Festival.
还有兰德鲁
And Landru.
兰德鲁？
Landru?
你问…
You ask--
你们形迹可疑
You are strange.
你们不屑盛典吗？
You scorn Festival?
对吗？
Are you--?
兰德鲁是怎么回事？
What about Landru?
盛典！盛典！
Festival! Festival!
兰德鲁
Landru.
我猜天亮前我们还有时间，别浪费时间
My guess is we have until morning. Let's put the time to good use.
医生，查查大气读本
Doctor, atmospheric readings
看看大气中是否有什么东西能解释这件事
to determine whether there's anything in the air to account for all this.
林斯特罗姆，把你看到的跟可能相关的
Mr. Lindstrom, correlate all that you've seen
一切社会学现象联系起来，如果有联系的话
with any other sociological parallels, if any.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
我们有要事要思考
You and I have some serious thinking to do.
明天一早离开之前
When we leave here tomorrow morning,
我希望能拿出具体的行动方案
I wanna have a plan of action.
盛典！
Festival!
史波克，史波克，林斯特罗姆
Spock. Spock. Lindstrom.
医生
Doc.
不不，都结束了，结束了，孩子
No, no, it's all over now. It's all over now, child.
没事了，没事了
It's all right. Quiet.
来，过来
Excuse me. Come on.
没事了
It's all right.
都结束了
It's all over.
他会给她打一针，让她安静下来，放心
He'll give her a shot. It'll calm her down. Trust us.
你甚至都不想办法救她回来
You didn't even try to bring her back.
你算是哪门子的父亲？
What kind of father are you?
这是兰德鲁的意志
It's Landru's will.
什么兰德鲁？他是谁？
What about Landru? Who is he?
这么说是真的咯
It is true then.
你们昨晚没有参加盛典
You did not attend the Festival last night.
没有
No.
那你们就不属于躯壳
Then you are not of the Body.
你们肯定不是
You couldn't be.
她睡着了
She is asleep.
你？
Are you--?
你们是执政官？
Are you Archons?
是又怎样？
What if we are?
据说一切都会接踵而来
It was said more would follow.
- 如果你们真的… - 我们得把他们藏起来
- If you are indeed-- - We must hide them.
快，立法者
Quickly. The Lawgivers.
朋友，我们自己能照顾自己
We can take care of ourselves, friend.
兰德鲁会知道的，他会来的
Landru will know. He will come.
就是他，他嘲笑立法者，我听见的
He is the one. He mocked the Lawgivers. I heard him.
不，韩寇，只是开个玩笑
No, Hacom. It was a jest.
其他人，都在这儿，他们轻蔑盛典
The others, they were here, but they scorned the Festival.
我看见了
I saw it.
塔玛，站开
Tamar, stand clear.
我听从兰德鲁的声音
I hear and obey the voice of Landru.
你们攻击了躯壳
You attack the Body.
听到了圣言却不服从
You have heard the word and disobeyed.
你们将被吸收
You will be absorbed.
“吸收”，什么意思？
What do you mean, "absorbed"?
看到了吗？
There, you see?
不属于躯壳
Not of the Body.
你们将被吸收
You will be absorbed.
一切安好
The good is all.
兰德鲁很温和
Landru is gentle.
你们会来的
You will come.
我们哪也不去
We're not going anywhere.
这是法律
It is the law.
你们必须得来
You must come.
我说，我们哪也不去
I said we're not going anywhere.
显然他们没做好应对决然反抗的准备
Evidently they are not prepared to deal with outright disobedience.
- 你怎么知道？ - 从目前所见来看
- How did you know? - Everything we've seen here so far
似乎是表明某种
seems to indicate some sort
强制性无意识刺激的行动
of compulsive involuntary stimulus to action.
分析得有理
Your analysis seems logical.
显然你们没太理解
It is clear that you simply did not understand.
我再说一遍
I will rephrase.
跟我们到吸收室来，这是命令
You are ordered to accompany us to the absorption chambers.
- 为什么要杀了那个老头？ - 主次不分
- Why did you kill that man? - Out of order.
你们会服从的
You will obey.
这是兰德鲁的圣言
It is the word of Landru.
你告诉兰德鲁
You tell Landru
该来的时候我们会来的
that we'll come in our own time
还要跟他对话
and that we'll speak to him.
你不能
You cannot.
他是兰德鲁
It is Landru.
兰德鲁
Landru.
有趣
Fascinating.
舰长，这只是个空心管
This is merely a hollow tube, captain.
没什么机械性
No mechanism.
他们在交流，我们有时间，跟我来
They're communing. We have time. Come with me.
- 去哪儿？ - 一个我知道的地方
- Where to? - To a place I know.
你们在那很安全，但动作得快点
You'll be safe there. But we must hurry.
兰德鲁会来的
Landru will come.
他们举行了一个好大的盛典
Quite a Festival they had.
平和
Peace.
你怎么看？
What do you make of all this?
完全不合逻辑
Totally illogical.
昨天，他们无缘无故地破坏
Yesterday, without apparent cause or reason, they wrought total havoc.
但今天，现在…
Yet today, now--
现在又恢复正常了
Now they're back to normal.
- 早上好，朋友们 - 早上好，比勒
- Morning, friends. - Good morning, Bilar.
你女儿，就是那个人
Your daughter, that's the man.
不，与比勒无关，是兰德鲁
No. It wasn't Bilar. It was Landru.
快点，我们没那么多时间
Let's hurry. We haven't much time.
太晚了，看
It's too late. Look.
怎么了？
What is it?
兰德鲁
Landru.
他在召唤躯壳
He's summoning the Body.
舰长，是感应
Telepathy, captain.
相位枪调为击昏模式
Phasers on stun.
雷格，怎么走？
Which way, Reger?
可能是那边，但兰德鲁…
Perhaps through there, but Landru...
我们来对付兰德鲁，快带我们离开这
We'll handle Landru. Just get us out of this.
我不想伤害他们，让他们退后
I don't wanna hurt them. Warn them back.
他们属于躯壳，是兰德鲁
They're in the Body. It's Landru.
相位枪调为击昏模式，大范围
Phasers on stun. Wide field.
开火
Fire.
- 安全 - 舰长
- Security. - Captain.
奥尼尔上尉，他是我们的人
Lieutenant O'Neil. He's one of our men.
- 现在不是了，他被吸收了 - 带着他
- Not anymore. He's been absorbed. - Bring him along.
但他现在是他们的人 一旦醒来，兰德鲁会通过他找到我们
But he's one of them. When he wakes, Landru will find us through him.
把他扔在这，他是我们的敌人，他被吸收了
Leave him there. He's our enemy. He's been absorbed.
我们已经找到奥尼尔，快点离开这里
We've got Lieutenant O'Neil. Let's beam up out of here.
我们还不知道执政官们发生了什么，哪边走？
We still don't know what's happened to the Archons. Which way?
带上他
Bring him along.
- 把他放那 - 一块光板
- Put him over there. - A lighting panel.
在这种文明里还真是神奇
Amazing in this culture.
这来自兰德鲁时代之前
Comes from a time before Landru.
兰德鲁时代之前？
Before Landru?
- 那是多久以前？ - 没人确切知道
- How long ago was that? - Nobody knows positively.
有人说大概是六千多年前
Some say as long ago as 6000 years.
舰长，这种装置需要很先进的科技
Captain, it took a very advanced technology
这跟这里的环境不符
to construct a device like this. Inconsistent with this environment.
但跟我们的所见很一致，警戒
But not inconsistent with what we've seen. Security.
那些东西
Those staffs.
中空管
Hollow tubes.
某种广播的天线
Antenna for some sort of broadcast power.
史波克，这是什么？
What is it, Mr. Spock?
有很强烈的电波
Immensely strong power generations, captain.
就在附近，但向四面八方辐射
Near here, but radiating in all directions.
他马上就醒了，舰长
He'll be coming around soon, captain.
不行
He must not.
他被吸收了
He's been absorbed.
- 吸收？ - 躯壳吸收他们的敌人
- Absorbed? - The Body absorbs its enemies.
迫不得已他们才杀人
It only kills when it has to.
第一批执政官到来的时候
When the first Archons came,
他们是自由的，不被控制，反对兰德鲁的意志
they were free, out of control, opposing the will of Landru.
很多人被杀了，但更多人被吸收
Many were killed. Many more were absorbed.
他一旦恢复意识，兰德鲁就会通过他找到我们
When he regains consciousness, Landru will find us through him.
- 如果其他人来了… - 什么其他人
- And if the others come-- - What others?
呃，就像你我一样，反对兰德鲁的人
Well, those like you and me who resist Landru.
地下组织？
An underground?
你怎么组织的？
How are you organised?
三个人
In threes.
我自己，死去的塔玛
Myself, Tamar, who's dead now,
- 还有另一个 - 谁？
- and one other. - Who?
不知道
I don't know.
塔玛是我的联络员
Tamar was my contact.
做决定吧，舰长，他快醒了
Give me a decision, captain. He's coming out of it.
不能让他恢复意识
He must not regain consciousness.
他会毁了我们大家的，他属于躯壳
He'll destroy us all. He is of the Body.
给他一针
Give him a shot.
让他睡着
Keep him asleep.
雷格
Reger.
我想弄清楚状况
I want some answers.
关于地下组织
This underground.
如果兰德鲁那么强大的话，你们是怎么幸存的呢？
If Landru is so powerful, how do you survive?
不知道
I don't know, captain.
我们中有些人逃脱了指令
Some of us escape the directives.
不多，但是有几个
Not many, but a few.
是第一批执政官来的时候
It was that way when the first Archons came.
执政官
The Archons.
告诉我是怎么回事
Tell me about them.
他们入侵了躯壳，但反对兰德鲁的意志
They had invaded the Body, but they resisted the will of Landru.
兰德鲁把他们从天上推了下去
You see, Landru had pulled them down from the skies.
从天上推下来？星舰？
Pulled them down from the skies? A starship?
史波克，你收集的那些力场读数，它们…？
Mr. Spock, those power readings you took, are they--?
有足够能力摧毁星舰吗？
Powerful enough to destroy a starship?
肯定
Affirmative.
寇克呼叫进取号，回话
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
舰长，我们遭到了袭击
Captain, we're under attack.
有发自星球表面的热射线发射过来
There are heat beams of some kind coming up from the planet's surface.
- 状态报告 - 我们的护盾在撑着
- Status report. - Our shields are holding,
但他们正在耗尽我们的能源
but they're taking all our power.
如果我们曲跃，或者继续驱动发动机
If we try to warp out, or even move on impulse engines,
我们就会失去护盾，并被烧成灰烬
we'll lose our shields, and we'll burn up like a cinder.
- 轨道状况如何？ - 检查中
- Orbit condition? - Checking.
我们在下降，舰长
We're going down, captain.
我们只有摆脱那些热射线，才能发动引擎
Unless we can get those beams off us so we can use our engines,
不超过12小时我们就会撞击大气
we're due to hit atmosphere in less than 1 2 hours.
继续开启护盾
Keep your shields up.
竭尽所能维系运行轨道
Do everything you can to maintain orbit.
我们会尝试追踪热射线来源并阻止它们
We'll try and locate the source of the beam and stop it here.
无法摆脱
Impossible to break away.
我尝试启用紧急电路，但毫无效果
I tried the emergency bypass circuits, but they haven't been effective.
舰长
Captain.
- 这是什么？ - 感应射线
- What is it? - Sensor beams.
很强烈，我们正被探测，在这个方向
Very strong. We're being probed, in this direction.
- 兰德鲁 - 阻截他们
- Landru. - Block them out.
太强烈了，无法阻截
Too strong, captain. Can't be blocked.
我是兰德鲁
I am Landru.
投影，舰长，虚幻的
Projection, captain. Unreal.
但很漂亮，在没有设备的情况下
But beautiful, Mr. Spock. With no apparatus at this end.
你是来毁坏的
You have come as destroyers.
你们带来了污染
You bring an infection.
你控制了我的星舰，我要求释放它
You're holding my ship. I demand that you release it.
你来到了一个没有恨
You have come to a world without hate,
没有恐惧
without fear,
没有冲突
without conflict.
没有战争
No war,
没有疾病
no disease,
没有犯罪
no crime.
没有古老罪恶的世界
None of the ancient evils.
兰德鲁为众生
Landru seeks tranquillity.
寻求安宁与平静
Peace for all.
宇宙的至善
The universal good.
我们没有恶意，我们的使命就是传播和平与善意
We mean you no harm. Ours is a mission of peace and goodwill.
善必将战胜恶
The good must transcend the evil.
理应如此
It shall be done.
所以从来如此
So it has been since the beginning.
他听不到你的话，舰长
He doesn't hear you, captain.
- 也许他能听这个的话 - 收起来
- Maybe he'll hear this. - Put that away.
兰德鲁
Landru.
- 听我说 - 你会被吸收的
- Listen to me. - You will be absorbed.
你的个性将会被合并到至善的联盟
Your individuality will merge into the unity of good.
在你被淹没于这个躯壳的时候
And in your submergence into the common being of the Body,
你会感受满足感和成就感
you will find contentment and fulfillment.
你会体验绝对的善
You will experience the absolute good.
舰长日志，星历3157.4
Captain's log, stardate 3157.4.
进取号仍然受到某种热射线攻击
The Enterprise, still under attack by some sort of heat rays
来自贝塔三号星球的表面
from the surface of Beta III,
现在星舰正由轮机长史考特指挥控制
is now being commanded by Engineering Officer Scott.
陆勤组已经被一个叫兰德鲁的生物抓获
The shore party has been taken by the creature called Landru.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
醒醒
Wake up.
莱斯利
Mr. Lesley.
麦考伊医生在哪里？
Where's Dr. McCoy?
我醒来时，他和其他守卫都不见了
He was gone when I woke up, along with the other guard
还有奥尼尔
and Mr. O'Neil.
我想他们来过这里又被转移了
I should say they've been here and been removed.
但这里是哪里？
But where is here?
显然，这是个看守最严的地方
Evidently, a maximum-security establishment.
- 你有武器吗？ - 我们全部的相位枪都不见了，我检查过了
- Are you armed? - All our phasers are gone. I checked.
那个锁住了
That's locked.
哦，我的头好疼
Oh, does my head ache.
遭受超声波影响后的正常反应
The natural result of being subjected to a hypersonic.
- 哦，那个就是？ - 声波
- Oh, is that what it was? - Sound waves.
再强些，它们就具有杀伤力，就是它们使我们失去了意识
Stronger, they might have killed. They rendered us unconscious.
分析到此为止
Enough analysis.
我们一起想想离开这里的办法
Let's think of a way to get out of here.
利用立法者无法解决意外之事的弱点怎么样？
What about the Lawgivers' inability to cope with the unexpected?
我不认为那会再次发生，舰长
I shouldn't depend on that happening again, captain.
在一个像这样秩序井然的社会
In a society as well organised as this one seems to be,
我无法想象这样一个疏忽会得不到纠正
I cannot conceive of such an oversight going uncorrected.
可是有趣的是
Interesting, however.
他们对你的抗拒的反应
Their reaction to your defiance was remarkably similar
很像一台数据不足或数据矛盾的计算机的反应
to the reaction of a computer, when fed insufficient or contradictory data.
你是不是在暗示着立法者只是计算机？
Are you suggesting that the Lawgivers are mere computers?
他们不是人类？
That they aren't human?
挺像人类的，舰长
Quite human, captain.
只是还不能看到全部的真相
It's simply that all the facts are not yet in.
还有缺口
There are gaps.
- 医生 - 哦，你好，朋友
- Doc. - Oh, hello, friend.
我们被告知在这里等候
We were told to wait here.
医生！
Doc!
有什么事吗，朋友？
Can I help you, friend?
- 你不认识我？ - 信奉兰德鲁的人都彼此认识
- Don't you know me? - We all know one another in Landru.
像苏鲁一样
Like Sulu.
想一想，伙计
Think, man.
进取号，星舰
The Enterprise. The ship.
记得吗？
Remember?
你说的话很奇怪，朋友
You speak very strangely, friend.
- 你来自别的地方吗？ - 你记得！
- Are you from away? - You do remember!
问兰德鲁吧
Ask Landru.
他记得
He remembers.
他知道，他注视着
He knows, and he watches.
你很奇怪
You are strange.
你不是躯壳的一员？
Are you not of the Body?
- 过来 - 不要
- Come. - No.
那么你会死去
Then you will die.
他们已经被纠正了，舰长
They've been corrected, captain.
你最好过去
You'd better go.
好吧
All right.
尽你所能
Work on Bones.
- 看一下你是不是能-- - 过来
- See if you can-- - Come.
麦考伊医生，他会怎么样？
Dr. McCoy, what will happen to him?
他会拥有快乐
He goes to joy.
平和与宁静
Peace and tranquillity.
他会去见兰德鲁
He goes to meet Landru.
幸福就是我们所有人都被兰德鲁所保佑
Happiness is to all of us blessed by Landru.
我是马普隆
I am Marplon.
现在是你的下班时间了
It is your hour.
交谈愉快
Happy communing.
谢谢
With thanks.
交谈愉快
Happy communing.
怎么样？
Well?
不可能
Impossible.
他受到极其强大的力量控制
He's under extremely powerful control.
我们打算一直在这里站下去吗？
Are we just gonna stand here?
我们能做的事不多
Little else we can do,
除非你能想出办法穿过那扇门
unless you can think of a way to get through that door.
这简直可笑至极
Well, this is simply ridiculous.
一群穿着长袍到处跑的原始人
A bunch of Stone-Age characters running around in robes.
和显然我们无法理解的控制力量
And apparently commanding powers far beyond our comprehension.
这不简单
Not simple.
也不可笑
Not ridiculous.
这非常，非常危险
Very, very dangerous.
你
You.
过来
Come.
祝你快乐，朋友
Joy to you, friend.
平和和满足将滋润你的心田
Peace and contentment will fill you.
你会了解兰德鲁的平和
You will know the peace of Landru.
不用害怕，朋友，那个作用是无害的
Have no fear, friend. The effect is harmless.
我叫马普隆
My name is Marplon.
我来不及救你的前两个朋友
I was too late to save your first two friends.
他们已经被吸收了
They have been absorbed.
小心他们
Beware of them.
- 舰长怎么样？ - 他没有被伤害，没有改变
- What about the captain? - He is unharmed. Unchanged.
我就是雷格三人组织中的第三人
I am the third man in Reger's triad.
我们一直在等待你们的归来
We have been awaiting your return.
我们不是执政官，马普隆
We are not Archons, Marplon.
你们怎么称呼自己都可以，你们实现了预言
Whatever you may call yourselves, you are in fulfillment of prophecy.
我们请求你们帮助
We ask your help.
- 雷格在哪里？ - 他会加入我们的
- Where is Reger? - He will join us.
他对吸收具有免疫力
He is immune to absorption.
快点！
Hurry!
- 我们没有多少时间了 - 谁是兰德鲁？
- We have not much time. - Who is Landru?
现在我不能回答你的问题
I cannot answer your questions now.
兰德鲁，他会听见的
Landru, he will hear.
这是你的武器
Here are your weapons.
你可能会用到它们
You may need them.
像你的舰长那样表现
Behave as you saw your captain behave.
完成了
It is done.
祝你快乐
Joy be with you.
平和和满足
Peace and contentment.
- 舰长 - 祝你平和与宁静
- Captain. - Peace and tranquillity to you.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
还好，小心麦考伊医生
Quite all right. Be careful of Dr. McCoy.
我知道
I understand.
- 兰德鲁？ - 我有一个推测，舰长
- Landru? - I am formulating a theory, captain.
是什么？
And?
不要在这里，医生
Not here. The doctor.
你们在奇怪地窃窃私语
You speak in strange whispers.
这不是兰德鲁的方式
This is not the way of Landru.
欢乐和宁静与你同在，朋友
Joy be yours, and tranquillity, my friend.
宁静与和谐
And peace and harmony.
你们是躯壳的一员吗？
Are you of the Body?
躯壳浑然一体
The Body is one.
祝福躯壳
Blessed be the Body,
祝愿它的各个部分安康
and health to all of its parts.
我的朋友
My friends.
你的推测是什么，史波克？
What is your theory, Mr. Spock?
这是一个没有灵魂的社会，舰长
This is a soulless society, captain.
它没有精神，没有朝气
It has no spirit, no spark.
真的都是平和与宁静
All is indeed peace and tranquillity.
工厂的平和，机器的宁静
The peace of the factory, the tranquillity of the machine,
各个部分都和谐共处
all parts working in unison.
当一些意料之外的事情发生了…
And when something unexplained happens...
…他们的程序被中断
...their routine is disrupted.
直到得到新的指令
Until new orders are received.
问题是，谁发出那些指令？
The question is, who gives those orders?
兰德鲁
Landru.
根本没有兰德鲁，舰长
There is no Landru, captain.
在人类的意义上
Not in the human sense.
英雄所见略同
You're thinking the same thing I am.
史波克，必须要拔掉插头
Mr. Spock, the plug must be pulled.
- 先生？ - 兰德鲁一定要死
- Sir? - Landru must die.
舰长，我们的首要指令是不予干预
Captain, our prime directive of non-interference.
那指的是一种活着的，成长中的文化
That refers to a living, growing culture.
你认为这个是吗？
Do you think this one is?
祝你们快乐，朋友
Joy to you all, friends.
这是兰德鲁的馈赠
It is the gift of Landru.
我带来了你们的信号设备
I brought your signalling devices.
你们可能要用到
You may need them.
我们真正需要的是关于兰德鲁的更多信息
What we really need is more information about Landru.
你说过你想我们帮你？
You said you wanted us to help you?
- 预言说-- - 别管预言说什么
- Prophecy says-- - Never mind what the prophecy says.
如果你想从兰德鲁手中获得解放
If you wanna be liberated from Landru,
- 我们需要你的帮助 - 舰长
- we'll need your help. - Captain.
- 你不属于躯壳！你不是！ - 愿你平和，朋友
- You're not of the Body! You're not! - Peace to you, friend.
立法者！
Lawgivers!
立法者！叛徒！叛徒！
Lawgivers! Traitor! Traitors!
- 我不想伤害你 - 叛徒！
- I don't wanna hurt you. - Traitors!
- 医生，我不想伤害你 - 叛徒！
- Doc, I don't wanna hurt you. - Traitors!
哦，医生
Oh, doc.
史波克！
Spock!
那是不是有点老土啊？
Isn't that somewhat old-fashioned?
长袍
Robes.
兰德鲁在哪里？
Where is Landru?
- 不，不 - 我们到哪里能找到他？
- No. No. - Where do we find him?
我们看不见他
We do not see him.
我们听见他的声音
We hear him,
在受众会堂
in the Hall of Audiences.
在这座建筑里？
In this building?
- 是的 - 你们要带我们去那里
- Yes. - You're gonna take us there.
- 不 - 史波克，呼叫进取号
- No. - Spock, call the Enterprise.
不
No.
振作起来
Snap out of it.
拿出你们的男子气概
Start acting like men.
史波克呼叫进取号，报告情况
Spock to Enterprise. Status report.
史波克先生，我一直尝试联系你
Mr. Spock, I've been trying to reach you.
- 报告，史考特 - 运行轨道仍然在衰减
- Report, Scott. - The orbit's still decaying.
最多能坚持六个小时，或多或少
Give it six hours, more or less.
那些热射线还在攻击我们，你要切断它们，史波克先生
Those heat beams are still on us. You've got to cut them off, Mr. Spock,
否则我们肯定会被烤熟的
or we'll cook one way or another.
史考特，坚持住，我们在尽我们所能
Scotty, stand by. We're doing the best we can.
苏鲁怎么样？
How's Mr. Sulu?
他很平和，但是很令我担忧
He's peaceful enough, but he worries me.
- 找个守卫看好他 - 看好苏鲁？
- Put a guard on him. - On Sulu?
那是命令
That's an order.
看好他，舰长完毕
Watch him. Captain out.
舰长
Captain.
好吧
All right.
关于兰德鲁
About Landru.
有一场战争
Well, there was war.
社会动乱，世界在自我毁灭
Convulsions. The world was destroying itself.
兰德鲁是我们的领袖
Landru was our leader.
他看到了真理
He saw the truth.
他改变了世界，他把我们带回去
He changed the world. He took us back.
带回到一个简单的时代
Back to a simple time.
一个平和宁静的时代
A time of peace and tranquillity.
他怎么了？
What happened to him?
他还活着
He's still alive.
他现在就在这里
He's here now.
他看得见，听得到
He sees, he hears.
我们已经毁了自己
We have destroyed ourselves.
拜托，不要再说了
Please, no more.
你说你想获得自由
You said you wanted freedom.
你要明白自由从来不是一种馈赠，而是要争取的
It's time you learned that freedom is never a gift. It has to be earned.
快说
Come on.
我们要找到兰德鲁
We're going to find Landru.
不！不，我错了！我服从
No! No, I was wrong! I submit.
我愿完全交出自己接受兰德鲁的意志！
I bare myself to the will of Landru!
- 那已经太晚了！ - 不要，立法者！救命！
- It's too late for that! - No. Lawgivers! Help!
救我！
Help me!
好了，现在看你的了
All right, it's up to you.
带我们去见兰德鲁
Take us to Landru.
这就是受众会堂
This is the Hall of Audiences.
- 打开它 - 但这是兰德鲁的--
- Open it. - But this is Landru.
打开它
Open it.
兰德鲁就在这里发表说话
Landru speaks here.
兰德鲁！
Landru!
我们就是执政官
We are the Archons!
我们就是执政官，我们来这里谈判
We are the Archons. We've come to speak.
我们就是执政官，我们想和你谈谈
We are the Archons. We wanna talk to you.
兰德鲁，他来了
Landru. He comes.
虽然我努力拯救你们
Despite my efforts to save you,
但你们入侵了躯壳，造成了巨大的损害
you have invaded the Nody, and you are causing great harm.
我们并不想造成损害
We have no intention of causing harm.
抹杀是必要的
Obliteration is necessary.
污染是严重的
The infection is strong.
为了躯壳的至善
For the good of the Nody,
你们一定要死
you must die.
这是一个悲剧
It is a great sorrow.
我们并不想死
We do not intend to die.
所有看见你的人
All who saw you,
所有知道你在此存在的人
all who know of your presence here,
一定要除去
must be excised.
躯壳的记忆会被清除
The memory of the Nody will be cleansed.
- 听我说 - 没用的，舰长
- Listen to me. - Useless, captain.
只是一个投影
A projection.
对，史波克
Yes, Mr. Spock.
让我们一起来看看本体吧
Let's have a look at the projector.
果然
Of course.
它就是
It had to be.
- 兰德鲁 - 一台机器
- Landru. - A machine.
这整个社会都是一台机器的完美概念
This whole society is a machine's concept of perfection.
- 平和，和谐 - 但是没有灵魂
- Peace, harmony. - But no soul.
我是兰德鲁
I am Landru.
你们这是入侵
You have intruded.
拔掉它的插头，史波克
Pull out its plug, Mr. Spock.
你们的设备已经被无效化了，你们也将会如此
Your devices have been neutralised. So it shall be with you.
我是兰德鲁
I am Landru.
兰德鲁在6000年前就已经去世了
Landru died 6000 years ago.
我是兰德鲁！我就是他！
I am Landru! I am he!
他所拥有的一切，我都有
All that he was, I am.
他的经验，他的知识
His experience, his knowledge.
但没有他的智慧
But not his wisdom.
他可能编写了你
He may have programmed you,
但他不能赋予你灵魂
but he could not have given you a soul.
你是一台机器
You are a machine.
你的表述是不相关的
Your statement is irrelevant.
你会被抹杀
You will be obliterated.
躯壳的至善是首要指令
The good of the Nody is the prime directive.
躯壳的至善，舰长
Good of the Body, captain.
那是关键
That's the key.
是的
Yes.
至善是什么？
What is the good?
我是兰德鲁
I am Landru.
兰德鲁已经死了，你是一台机器
Landru is dead. You are a machine.
你收到了一个问题，回答它
A question has been put to you. Answer it.
至善是躯壳和谐的
The good is the harmonious continuation
延续
of the Nody.
至善是平和，宁静
The good is peace, tranquillity.
躯壳的至善是首要指令
The good of the Nody is the directive.
那么我告诉你你违反了首要指令
Then I put it to you that you have disobeyed the prime directive.
你损害了躯壳
You are harmful to the Body.
躯壳是--
The Body is--
它存在，它是健全的
It exists. It is healthy.
躯壳濒临死亡
The Body is dying.
你在破坏它
You are destroying it.
你在问问题吗？
Do you ask a question?
你做了什么…
What have you done
去公正对待躯壳的每个个体的潜能？
to do justice to the full potential of every individual of the Body?
数据不足
Insufficient data.
没有选择的自由，就没有创造性
Without freedom of choice, there is no creativity.
没有创造性，就没有生命
Without creativity, there is no life.
躯壳死了
The Body dies.
是你的错
The fault is yours.
你在帮助躯壳还是在破坏它？
Are you aiding the Body, or are you destroying it?
我的程序不是用来回答那个问题的
I am not programmed to answer that question.
兰德鲁，指导我们
Landru, guide us.
兰德鲁
Landru.
没有必要，舰长
Not necessary, captain.
他们没有指引来处理这种情况 这可能是他们生命中的第一次
They have no guidance, possibly for the first time in their lives.
兰德鲁
Landru,
回答我的问题
answer the question.
平和，秩序和宁静在维持着
Peace, order and tranquillity are maintained.
躯壳活着
The Body lives.
但是我自己保留着创造性
But I reserve creativity to me.
那躯壳死了
Then the Body dies.
创造性对躯壳的健全是必要的
Creativity is necessary for the health of the Body.
这是不可能的
This is impossible.
- 这真的是兰德鲁吗？ - 他还剩下什么
- Is this truly Landru? - What's left of him,
在6000年前他建造和编写这部机器以后
after he built and programmed this machine 6000 years ago.
你一定要创造至善
You must create the good.
那就是兰德鲁的意志，别无他物
That is the will of Landru, nothing else.
但是有罪恶
But there is evil.
一定要毁灭罪恶
Then the evil must be destroyed.
那是首要指令，而你就是罪恶
That is the prime directive, and you are the evil.
我思考！我活着！
I think! I live!
你就是罪恶
You are the evil.
一定要毁灭罪恶
The evil must be destroyed.
完成首要的指令
Fulfill the prime directive.
- 你就是罪恶 - 兰德鲁，救我
- You are the evil. - Landru, help me.
完成首要的指令
Fulfill the prime directive.
救我！救我！救我！救我！
Help me! Help me! Help me! Help me!
马普隆，现在你要靠自己了，我希望你已经准备好了
Well, Marplon, you're on your own now. I hope you're up to it.
你可以摆脱那些长袍了
You can get rid of those robes.
如果我是你，我会开始找份新工作
If I were you, I'd start looking for another job.
寇克呼叫进取号，回应
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in.
- 舰长，你没事吧？ - 星舰怎么样？
- Captain, are you all right? - What about the ship?
热射线已经消失了，舰长，苏鲁先生也已经恢复正常
The heat rays have gone, captain, and Mr. Sulu's back to normal.
接你班
Relieving you.
太好了，史考特
Excellent, Scotty.
准备传送陆勤组
Stand by to beam up landing party.
我们一起去看看其他人怎么样，马普隆可以收拾好这里
Let's go see how the others are doing. Marplon can finish up here.
舰长日志，星历3158.7
Captain's log, stardate 3158.7.
进取号准备离开位于C-111星系的贝塔三号星球
The Enterprise is preparing to leave Beta III in star system C-111.
社会学家林斯特罗姆和一群专家留下来
Sociologist Lindstrom is remaining behind with a party of experts
他们会帮助恢复这个星球的文化到人类的形式
who will help restore the planet's culture to a human form.
- 真是了不起 - 什么？
- Marvellous. - What?
已故的兰德鲁，舰长
The late Landru, captain.
了不起的工程壮举
Marvellous feat of engineering.
一台能操控数百万人类生命的计算机
A computer capable of directing the lives of millions of human beings.
但它仅仅是一台机器，史波克
But only a machine, Mr. Spock.
原版的兰德鲁穷尽毕生所学编制了它
The original Landru programmed it with all his knowledge,
但是他却无法赋予它他的智慧，他的怜悯
but he couldn't give it his wisdom, his compassion,
他的理解，他的灵魂，史波克
his understanding, his soul, Mr. Spock.
可预见的形而上学
Predictably metaphysical.
我更喜欢实在的，可抓住的，可证明的东西
I prefer the concrete, the graspable, the provable.
你会做出一台出色的计算机，史波克
You'd make a splendid computer, Mr. Spock.
你过奖了，舰长
That is very kind of you, captain.
舰长，林斯特罗姆先生请求通话
Captain, Mr. Lindstrom from the surface.
你好，林斯特罗姆
Yes, Lindstrom.
只是想说声再见，舰长
Just wanted to say goodbye, captain.
- 进展如何？ - 好得不能再好了
- How's it going? - Couldn't be better.
今早我们已经有六宗家庭纠纷
Already this morning we've had half a dozen domestic quarrels
和两起一边倒的斗殴
and two genuine knockdown drag-outs.
这里可能不是天堂，但肯定是个人类的世界
It may not be paradise, but it's certainly human.
听起来很有前途
Sounds most promising.
祝你好运
Good luck.
人类渴望多久了
How often mankind has wished for a world as peaceful
一个像兰德鲁提供的那样平静和安全的世界
and secure as the one Landru provided.
是的，我们从未得到
Yes, and we never got it.
不过很幸运，我想
Just lucky, I guess.
本集结束
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/